Ryan O'Mullan

Irish, Single, 27 years old

São Paulo - Brazil

Telephone: +55 (11) 9 4843-5511 Email: omullan.ryan@gmail.com

Skype: ryanomullan

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/ryanomullan/pt

Summary

Trilingual English / French / Portuguese

International Experience: France, Germany, Brazil

Experience with Sales and Web Development in the Health, Finance and Digital Marketing Industry. Interest in the areas of Business Intelligence, Data Science, Startups, Business, and Web Development.

Education

Master: Web Engineering - Senac São Paulo, Brazil (03/2015 - 12/2016)

Bachelor: Commercialization of Products and Industrial Services - Université Toulouse III, France (09/2011 - 09/2012)

DUT: Electronics and Industrial Informatics - Université de Limoges, France (09/2009 - 06/2011)

Skills

IT

- Python, Django, Postgres, SQL, MongoDB, Git, Linux, HTML, CSS.
- Moderate knowledge: Javascript, Java, Spring, R, Scala, C, Delphi, AWS and Docker.
- Google Analytics, Photoshop and Excel.

Business

- Business Intelligence, CRM, Sales, Negotiation and International Development.
- MailChimp, Microsoft Office e Sage CRM.

Certificates

- Mobile App Analytics Fundamentals Google
- Google Analytics Platform Principles Google

Languages

- Native English- Lived in Ireland for 12 years
- Native French Lived in France for 10 years
- Fluent Portuguese Currently living in Brazil
- Basic German Lived in Germany for 2 years
- Basic Spanish

Professional Experience

Jr Software Engineer - PagueMob, Brazil (04/2016 - Today)

- Creating RESTful APIs in Scala, Java and Python.
- Main Technologies: Scala, Play Framework, Java, Spring, Python, Postgres, Docker and AWS.

Web Developer - Freelance (12/2013 - Today)

- Building responsive websites for mobile and desktop devices.
- Managing websites, social media and marketing email.
- Main Technologies: Python/Django, Postgres, Javascript, Bootstrap, Git, Heroku, MailChimp.
- Portfolio: http://ryan.omullan.com/

Web Developer - Zenvia Mobile Results, Brazil (04/2015 - 04/2016)

- Development of RESTful APIs for an AdServer
- Creating B.I. reports
- Automating various tasks using Python scripts.
- Monitoring and creating reports for the performance of advertising campaigns.
- Validating advertising material: Images, HTML and JavaScript.
- Main Technologies: Python/Django, Javascript, MongoDB, Postgres, Django Rest Framework, Git and highcharts.is

International Account Manager - nal von minden GmbH, Germany (04/2012 - 10/2013)

- Selling medical equipment to French and International distributors.
- Managing Key Clients.
- Customer and technical support.
- Creating promotional and marketing material
- Participating in international fairs and visits to clients.

Marketing Assistant - Alias Invest, France (11/2011 - 02/2012)

- Creating marketing material for the company's website: www.alias-invest.com
- Benchmarking competitors.

ERASMUS Internship - University of Regensburg, Germany (04/2011 - 06/2011)

- Designing the layout of circuit boards with CadSoft EAGLE.
- Programming microcontrollers in C.

Professional University Project - Université de Limoges, France (09/2010 - 03/2011)

• Creating and designing an educational desktop program using Delphi 7 for a school of poly-handicapped children.